<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Python on Chris Muthig</title>
    <link>https://camuthig.dev/tags/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Python on Chris Muthig</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://camuthig.dev/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Custom Django Fields</title>
      <link>https://camuthig.dev/posts/django_drf_custom_object_id_field/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://camuthig.dev/posts/django_drf_custom_object_id_field/</guid>
      <description>I recently needed to implement a special kind of field in Django Rest Framework that turned out to be a fun experiment. I recreated this in a simple Django application, and the bulk of the DRF-related code can be found here.
First, the API used a hashed ID. So the primary key from the database was taken, additional information added to it and then hashed.
Second, the API to set the relationship value behaved differently than when reading it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Version and Dependency Management</title>
      <link>https://camuthig.dev/posts/python-version-dependency-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://camuthig.dev/posts/python-version-dependency-management/</guid>
      <description>I have only been a professional Python developer for three months. I made this transition after several years in the PHP ecosystem, and I am still learning some nuances of Python. One area I have found very challenging is version and dependency management. I think it has been hard for me because it was a pretty simple concept in PHP. For versions, I didn&amp;rsquo;t often change them, but when I did, I would usually unlink the current PHP binaries and link up new ones through some sort of script.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing on Windows Using WSL 2</title>
      <link>https://camuthig.dev/posts/windows-development-wsl2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://camuthig.dev/posts/windows-development-wsl2/</guid>
      <description>I just ran across this draft on my machine after several months (I wrote this in January), so hopefully it is clean enough and I believe the information is still up to date.
Below are my thoughts and experience setting up and testing the use of Window&amp;rsquo;s WSL 2 system for development work. The findings are based on running a production-ready Django application, but only doing minor modifications to test how the development flow works.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>